

Coach, intellectually curious team player with proven leadership abilities with a **Master's degree in Business administration & Engineering degree**. Interested in a Managing position at an international company. to apply experience reviewing blueprints and specifications, **With 15+ years of Executive Management & project management experience** in mega Telecommunication Projects. Also coming with highly Entrepreneurial skills time management, planning, budgeting, and solid negotiation skills, Business development management heading up their expansion in new markets as well as continued expansion

AHMAD ALSHAROUNI

CONTACT

Phone:

+965 66649100

Email:

ahmad.sharouni@outlook.com

LinkedIn:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/ahmad-al-sharouni-a9b87324/

Address:

Via San Felice, 14, Bologna, Italy

Date of birth:

15/05/1984

Nationality:

Egyptian

LANGUAGES

English: fluent

Arabic: mother tongue

EDUCATION

Sep - 2019 - June2021

Master's Degree Global MBA in Supercars, Superbikes & Motorsports Bologna Business School, University of Bologna, Italy



Sep - 2001 - Jan 2007

Bachelor's Degree (B.S.C.E) in Electrical Engineering (Communication and Computer)

The Higher Technological Institute, Ramadan Tenth City, Egypt



WORK EXPERIENCE

03/2018 – present Essential Projects Management Co. - CEO & Founder (Kuwait) 02/2017 – present Splenor General Trading – CEO & Founder (Kuwait) 09/2016 – present: First Knight B.V – CEO & Founder (Netherlands)

- Heading the board of directors and conducting the board meetings
- Develop and manage Business Strategy & Business Planning
- Planning all the future strategies of the company and implementing those strategies
- Assigning duties and responsibilities to the heads of departments
- Lead the development and execution of strategic partnership and sales channel strategies to drive revenue across multiple lines of business
- Fixing the annual Finance plans & budgets of all the departments,
- Setting goals for the company to achieve & Prepared organization for forecasted demand levels through effective operational planning.
- Developed and implemented strategic updates to service operations to solve issues affecting
 efficiency, profitability and production
- Meeting with clients and future business partners and expanding the business of the company
- Negotiated terms of business acquisitions to increase business base, solidify market presence and diversify offerings.
- Devised new promotional approaches to boost customer numbers and market penetration while enhancing engagement and driving growth.
- Conducting performance reviews, appraisals & press conferences on behalf of the company
- Take responsibility of the profits of the company and set targets for them to achieve
- Do risk assessment for future business prospects & build up risk management plan
- Creating, negotiating and closing commercial agreements
- Managed partnerships and strategic business relationships by negotiating contract terms and handling conflicts.
- Develop and manage customer satisfaction process
- Working closely with the human resources department and creating a good working environment for the employees and managing the recruiting process
- Coached and guided senior managers to improve effectiveness and policy enforcement, resulting in improved employee job satisfaction and higher performance levels
- Monitored use of best practices at levels and implemented corrective actions to bring employees into compliance
- Successfully led teams of employees in several locations.
- Looking after all the legal issues of the company and representing the company if required

SKILL HIGHLIGHTS

- Business development
- Project management
- Strong decision maker
- Complex problem solver
- Critical thinking
- Problem-solving
- Contract negotiation
- Conflict resolution
- Budgeting
- Planning
- Communication skills

SOFTWARE



WORK EXPERIENCE

02/2002 - present: International Import & Export Co - General Manager (Egypt)

- Managing implementation and commissioning for communication project
- Studying the communication project scope of works, clients' requirement, BOQ, project milestones, and specification
- Engineering services, analysis & Design
- among existing clients
- Building relationships with existing clients in an attempt to increase their current spend
- Driving peak performance and sales success across the organization
- Supporting in local procurement of material, equipment
- Creating, negotiating and closing commercial agreements
- Instrumental in devising and implementing the strategy for meeting sales performance targets
- Responsible for heading up their expansion in new markets as well as continuing expansion

04/2012 - 02/2017 Peak National Contracting Co - Business Development Manager & Communication Project Manager (Kuwait)

- Managed implementation and commissioning for communication projects
- Studied the communication project scope of works, clients' requirement, BOQ, project milestones, and specification
- Engineering Server & Controller cabinets
- Network design and construction
- Design & implement Security systems
- Configuration of Ethernet switches
- Responsible for heading up their expansion in new markets as well as continued expansion among existing clients
- Building relationships with existing clients in an attempt to increase their current spend
- Drive peak performance and sales success across the organization
- Support in local procurement of material, equipment
- Create, negotiate and close commercial agreements
- Instrumental in devising and implementing the strategy for meeting sales performance targets

01/2011 - 02/2012: Luthardt General Electrical Contracting Co - Senior Communication Engineer (Germany)

- Design, installation and integration for Communication system & Networks for ABB water distillation plants and control system in several projects such as: KSA Ras Zor - Riyadh water distillation plant, UAE Abu Dhabi water distillation plant, CCTV, Security systems, Baku port, Kuwait Mina Abdullah distillation plant
- Contribution in cost and calculations the direct & Indirect Cost for Communication system & Networks in projects
- Engineering Support to Project Manager (support and substitute of Project Manager in case of absence)
- Support of Project Manager in the selection of local stuff
- Support in local procurement of communication material & equipment
- Support in communication and transfer of assignments to local staff and their supervision
- Participation on customer meetings, on meetings with ABB Subcontractors
- Design & implement Security systems networks
- Network design and implement
- Configuration of Ethernet switches
- Telecommunications Transmission design

04/2008 – 01/2011: Sultan Telecom Company (Kuwait) Project Manager (09/2008 – 01/2011)

- Project Manager and executive supervisor for implementation, integration and commissioning Huawei equipment (3G&2G) at sites & network infrastructure for (VIVA) 3rd Mobile Operator in Kuwait project value 50,000,000 \$ HUAWEI BTS Commissioning:1-Commissioning of BTS3012 / 2-Commissioning of BTS3812E / 3-Commissioning of BTS3900 (3G) /4-Commissioning of E NodeB (4G)
- Project Manager for 4G trial Network
- Project Manager for CCTV installation system for KNPC Al Ahmadi refinery
- Project Manager for installing wireless system for all Sultan-Center (MAN) Network

WORK EXPERIENCE

04/2008 - 01/2011: Sultan Telecom Company (Kuwait)

Tender & Proposal Manager (06/20110-01/2011)

- Study the project scope of works, clients' requirement, BOQ, project milestones, and specification from the supplied bid documents
- Review of information about demands and derivation of supply and proposal preparations
- Clarification of bid conditions and management of the tender preparation
- Monitoring of the bid management in order to ensure it is aligned with the organization's requirements
- Contribution in cost and price calculations the direct & Indirect Cost of the project,
- Coordinate with Planning Engineer for the Construction Schedule,
- Coordination of tender reviews and deadlines and adjust them to the frameworks given by the

Senior Communication Engineer (04/2008 – 09/2008)

- Installation and commissioning of HUAWEI BTS Commissioning:1-Commissioning of BTS3012 / 2-Commissioning of BTS3812E / 3-Commissioning of BTS3900 (3G) /4-Commissioning of NodeB E-NodeB (4G)
- **HUAWEI MW insulation & Commissioning**
- Fiber Optics insulation & Commissioning

Available upon request

TRAINING EXPERIENCE

Trained in each place of the follow for three and half months for each place:

- At the Higher technology institute of 10th of Ramadan
- ABB Arab
- Siemens (Bio medical solution)
- Web Designing course

Training Course Attended and Certifications:

- **CCNA**
- CDMA (At High Tech. Center Faculty of Engineering -Cairo University)
- UMTS (At High Tech. Center Faculty of Engineering –Cairo University)
- PMP Project management Professional (amideast)
- Fundamentals of Risk Management (OCRM Organization of Certified Risk Managers)
- Fundamentals Digital Marketing (Google Digital work shop & IAP)
- E-Commerce (eMarketing Institute)
- Online Marketing Fundamentals (eMarketing Institute)
- SEO Certification (eMarketing Institute)
- Search Engine Marketing Certification (eMarketing Institute)
- Social Media Marketing Certification (eMarketing Institute)

Huawei Training

- Training on OSP Project at Huawei Kuwait
- Training on TE (2G BTS & 3G nodeb & 4G enodeb commissioning and installation)
- MW Huawei equipment installation (optix RTN 600 Series) at Huawei Kuwait
- **HUAWEI BTS Commissioning:**
- **HUAWEI MW Commissioning optix RTN 600**

REFERENCES